# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频为大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I will share a homestyle dish with you.
# 鸭蛋炒菠菜
Stir-fried Duck Egg with Spinach
# 首先我们准备鸭蛋6个打入盆中
First let's prepare 6 duck eggs and crack them into a bowl.
# 盆中加入食用盐1大勺（约3克）
Add 1 spoon of table salt (about 3 grams) to the bowl.
# 加入少许胡椒粉
Add a dash of white pepper powder.
# 加入适量的面粉之后顺着一个方向搅拌均匀备用
Add a bit of flour and mix well in one direction.
# 同学们面粉可以增加鸭蛋下锅成型的速度
The flour can increase the speed of egg formation in the wok.
# 也可以吸收多余的水分
It also absorbs excess water.
# 下一步我们开始处理菠菜
Next let's move on to the spinach.
# 准备适量的菠菜切掉根部备用
Prepare a generous amount of spinach with the roots cut off.
# 喜欢吃菠菜梗的同学也可以忽略
Those who like spinach stems can leave the roots on.
# 然后我们首先在锅中加入适量的清水开大火烧开
Then add some water to a wok on high heat
# 中途加入适量的食用盐
Add some table salt into the water.
# 大火烧开之后下入菠菜焯水至断生
Bring to a boil over high heat and blanch the spinach until they are half cook.
# 同学们焯水的时候一定要放入适量的植物油保色
Need to add some vegetable oil to preserve the color of spinach during blanching.
# 否则波菜出锅之后很容易发黄变味
Otherwise, the spinach will be easily yellowed and tasteless after blanching.
# 断生之后捞出放入冷水中透凉备用
After they are half cooked, remove from heat and let spinach cool in cold water.
# 这一步在我们的行业之中称为“过冷河”
This step is called "crossing cold river" in Chinese cooking terms.
# 透亮之后捞出攥干水分备用
Allow the spinach to cool, then drain and squeeze out the water.
# 有条件的同学也可以用厨房纸吸干水分
You can also use kitchen towels to absorb water if you want.
# 去除水分之后将菠菜切成2厘米左右的小段备用了
After removing the water from the spinach, cut it into 2 cm sections.
# 最后将其搅拌均匀备用
Finally, stir it all together with the egg.
# 下一步开始制作
Start cooking them next.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First let's heat up the wok.
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
Once the wok is hot, add a generous amount of oil to grease the wok.
# 滑好锅之后将热油倒出
After greasing the wok, pour out the hot oil.
# 再加入适量的底油烧热之后下入调好的菠菜蛋液
Add some base oil and pour in the spinach egg mixture.
# 然后转小火先将蛋液煎至成型
Then turn the heat down to low and fry the egg mixture until it forms.
# 蛋液成型之后用炒勺轻轻地推散
Once the egg mixture is formed, gently push it into pieces with a frying spoon.
# 中途可以适当地晃锅翻面
You can shake the wok and turn it over during the process.
# 蛋液基本成型之后再转中火翻炒煎制
Once the egg is formed, turn the heat to medium and fry.
# 将鸭蛋炒香煎香之后翻几下即可出锅装盘
Finally toss the egg a few times and it's ready to serve.
# 一道非常美味的鸭蛋炒菠菜就制作完成
A very tasty stir-fried duck egg with spinach is ready!
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一
First,
# 菠菜不管是生炒还是滚汤
For spinach, either is stir-fry or making soup,
# 最好事先焯水
is better to blanch in advance.
# 这样可以有效去除涩味和草酸
This effectively removes astringency and oxalic acid.
# 第二
Second,
# 绿壳鸭蛋和白壳鸭蛋并无明显区别
There is no significant difference between green and white duck eggs.
# 不喜欢鸭蛋的同学也可以选择鹅蛋或者鸡蛋
For those who don't like duck eggs, you can also choose goose eggs or normal eggs.
# 第三
Third,
# 蛋液在搅动的时候尽量挑高
Try to pick up the egg mixture as high as possible when you stir it up
# 这样可以吸收空气进入
It will absorb more air.
# 从而使蛋液下锅不容易煎糊
So that the eggs don't burn in the wok during stir-frying.
# 鸭蛋炒菠菜的技术总结完毕
That's all for the technique summary for Stir-fried Duck Egg with Spinach.